Guide to the Christian Conference of Asia Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
Christian Conference of Asia Records
1946-2008
RG 237
Yale University Divinity School Library
182
(182 boxes)
These are the official archives of the Christian Conference of Asia, a regional ecumenical organization representing church councils and denominations in Australia, Bangladesh, Burma, Cambodia, East Timor, Hong Kong, India, Indonesia, Laos, Japan, Korea, Malaysia, New Zealand, Pakistan, Philippines, Sri Lanka, Taiwan and Thailand. The CCA began as the East Asia Christian Conference in 1957 and changed its name to Christian Conference of Asia in 1973.
Christian Conference of Asia
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Christian Conference of Asia
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
1947 At the International Missionary Council meeting at Whitby, East Asian delegates suggested a conference to plan for an Asian office.
1949 Eastern Asia Christian Conference held in Bangkok.
1951 Rajah B. Manikam appointed as Joint Secretary for East Asia for the International Missionary Council (IMC) and World Council of Churches (WCC).
1954 Asia Council on Ecumenical Mission (ACEM) formed.
1957 IMC, WCC, and ACEM came together at Prapat, Indonesia for constituting assembly of the East Asia Christian Conference "The Common Evangelistic Task of the Churches in East Asia."
1959 2nd General Assembly of East Asia Christian Conference (EACC) held at Kuala Lumpur - "Witnessing Together."
1959-1964 Dr. D. T. Niles served as General Secretary.
1964 3rd General Assembly of EACC held in Bangkok - "The Christian Community within the Human Community"
1968 4th General Assembly of EACC held in Bangkok - "In Christ All Things Hold Together."
1968-1973 Mr. U Kyaw Than served as General Secretary.
1973 5th General Assembly held in Singapore - "Christian Action in the Asian Struggle." Name of organization changed to Christian Conference of Asia (CCA).
1973-1985 Rt. Rev. Dr. Yap Kim Hao served as General Secretary.
1974 Asia Sunday instituted. Singapore office opened.
1976 First Asian Ecumenical Center event held, later known as Asia Ecumenical Course.
1977 6th General Assembly held in Penang - "Jesus Christ in Asian Suffering and Hope."
1981 7th General Assembly held in Bangalore - "Living with Christ in People."
1982 Ecumenical Council on Third World Tourism set up.
1985 8th General Assembly held in Seoul - "Jesus Christ Sets Free to Serve." Indonesian churches withdraw from active participation in CCA.
1985-1990 Rev. Dr. Park Sang Jung served as General Secretary.
1987 CCA expelled from Singapore.
1988 CCA staff dispersed to Osaka, Hong Kong, Manila, and Chiang Mai.
1989 Asian Mission Conference, Indonesia.
1990 9th General Assembly held in Manila - "Christ Our Peace: Building a Just Society." Indonesian churches re-activate CCA membership.
1990-1995 Rt. Rev. John Samuel served as General Secretary.
1991 Land purchased in Hong Kong for new CCA center
1993 CCA Center at Shatin dedicated. Conferences held: Asian Students and Youth Gathering, Asian Church Leaders' Conference on Migrant Workers, Refugees, Internally Displace Communities in Asia (MRIA)
1994 Asian Mission Conference, Korea
1995 10th General Assembly held in Colombo - "Hope in God in a Changing Asia." Proposal towards new thrust and new structures. Asian Church Leaders' Conference on Indochina.
1995 June - December Rev. Dr. Toshitsugu Arai served as Acting General Secretary.
1996-2000 Dr. Feliciano V. Carino served as General Secretary.
1996 Joint effort with Federation of Asian Bishops' Conferences (FABC): Asian Movement for Christian Unity (AMCU). First CCA program in China (Youth).
1997 Formation of Congress of Asian Theologians.
2000 11th General Assembly held in Tomohon - "Time of Fullness of Life for All"
2000 June -2005 July Dr. Ahn Jae Woong served as General Secretary.
2005 12th General Assembly held in Chiang Mai - "Building Communities of Peace for All."
2005 August - 2010 July Dr. Prawate Khidard served as General Secretary.
2006 CCA office moved from Hong Kong to Chiang Mai.
2010 13th General Assembly held in Kuala Lumpur - "Called to Prophesy, Reconcile and Heal."
2010 August - 2015 July Rev. Dr. Henriette Hutabarat Lebang served as General Secretary.
2015 14th General Assembly held in Jakarta.
2015 August Mathews George Chunakara appointed General Secretary.
Scope and Contents
This collection provides extensive valuable documentation of the development of ecumenical Christianity in Asia from the mid-20th century through the early 2000s. The East Asia Christian Conference, formed in 1957 and renamed Christian Conference of Asia in 1973, grew out of earlier efforts of the International Missionary Council and World Council of Churches to support and encourage the development of Christian churches and Asian Christian leaders in Asia. From its foundation, the Christian Conference of Asia has focused on mission, leadership development, ecumenical relationships, and issues of social justice in Asia.
The records are valuable for their documentation of the organizational development of ecumenical Christianity in Asia but also for the insight they provide on a wide variety of social issues in Asia such as development, health, refugees, disabilities, gender, globalization, labor, and other social justice issues. Because CCA networked with so many other religious organizations in Asia and throughout the world, this collection provides valuable insight on the worldwide ecumenical movement throughout the last half of the 20th century.
A large and complex archive, the records in this collection migrated with the CCA throughout Asia as the organization had its headquarters in various countries. The offices and program desks of the CCA were somewhat decentralized and often kept parallel records so there is some overlap and duplication in the archival record. Some records had been compiled and described by the organization in previous years while other similar records were completely unorganized. An effort has been made to rationalize the structure of the archives according to CCA's various leaders, program units, and functions, but it is recommended that the researcher use keyword searching of the finding aid to locate all materials related to any particular event,issue, or person.
Note that many pamphlets and books published by the Christian Conference in Asia are in the Yale Divinity Library's cataloged collection rather than in this archival collection. A search for Christian Conference in Asia as "Publisher" in Orbis results in nearly 200 hits.
For additional description of the history and program activities of the CCA, see From Prapat to Colombo: history of the Christian Conference of Asia (1957-1995) by Yap Kim Hao, and other works in the Library's cataloged collection. The website of the CCA also provides historical information about the organization and a valuable listing of its leaders and staff members over the years: http://cca.org.hk/home/cca-history/.
Arrangement
I. Organization and Policy Records
II. Administrative Records
III. General Secretary / Associate General Secretary Files
IV. Program Areas / Activities
V. Publications
VI. CCA Assemblies / Conferences
VII. Related Organizations / Conferences
VIII. Audio-Visual Materials
IX. Financial Records
Christian Conference of Asia
- Organization and Policy Records, Series I
  - Legal documentation
    - Published constitutions
      - EACC, 1968, 1971 (Box 101, Folder 1)
      - CCA, 1973, 1975, 1985, 1995 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and proposals
      - EACC Continuation Committee proposals, 1971 (Box 101, Folder 3)
      - Proposed revisions to constitution, ca. 1974 (Box 101, Folder 4)
      - Constitutional Review Committee reports, drafts, correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 101, Folder 5-7)
      - Member responses to proposed changes, 1991-1994 (Box 101, Folder 8)
      - Related to legal status in Hong Kong; Articles of Association of Christian Conference of Asia (Hong Kong) Ltd., 1992-1996 (Box 101, Folder 9-10)
      - Hong Kong Inland Revenue Department correspondence, 1994 (Box 101, Folder 11)
      - Proposed amendments to constitution, 1995 (Box 101, Folder 12)
      - Proposed amendments to constitution, 1999 (Box 101, Folder 13)
  - History
    - General overviews
      - "The East Asia Christian Conference: A Study of its History and Development 1938-1956" by Dietmar Hubner, 1963 (Box 101, Folder 14)
        Scope and Contents
        First draft of thesis, Union Theological Seminary, Philippines
      - "Christian Conference of Asia: A historical overview" by T. V. Philip, 1992 (Box 101, Folder 15)
      - "A Short Sketch of the First 25 Years of CCA" by Park Sang Jung, No date (Box 101, Folder 16)
      - Chronology and other brief historical sketches, 2000, no date (Box 101, Folder 17)
    - Pre-EACC / formation era
      - Correspondence of Rajah B. Manikam, 1947-1956 (Box 101, Folder 18-23)
        Manikam was the first Joint Secretary for East Asia of the World Council of Churches and International Missionary Council.
      - Travel diaries of Rajah B. Manikam, 1951-1956 (Box 101, Folder 24-27)
      - Reports of Manikam; essay entitled "Some Concerns of Younger Churchmen", 1951-1956 (Box 101, Folder 28)
      - Minutes of Meeting of the Joint Commission on East Asia of the IMC and WCC, Manila, 1948 (Box 101, Folder 29)
      - Christian Prospect in Eastern Asia - papers and minutes of the Eastern Asia Christian Conference, Bangkok, 1949, 1950 (Box 102, Folder 20)
      - The Church in East Asia - findings of the East Asian Christian Conference, Bangkok, 1949, 1950 (Box 102, Folder 21)
      - Minutes of IMC/WCC consultation, Bangkok, 1956 (Box 102, Folder 22)
      - Excerpt from minutes of World Council of Churches Central Committee, New Haven, re. formation of EACC, 1957 (Box 102, Folder 23)
    - Expulsion from Singapore
      - Government documents / legal correspondence
        - Singapore Ministry of Home Affairs press release, 1987 December 30 (Box 101, Folder 30)
        - Statutes of the Republic of Singapore: Societies Act (Chapter 311), 1985 (Box 101, Folder 31)
        - Correspondence with government offices, 1988 January-July (Box 101, Folder 32)
        - CCA correspondence with attorneys, Khattar, Wong & Partners, 1988 January-July (Box 101, Folder 33)
      - CCA statements
        - Statement of Rev. Park Sang Jung, General Secretary, 1988 January 18 (Box 101, Folder 34)
        - Memoranda, statements sent to member churches and councils, 1988-1989 (Box 101, Folder 35)
        - Resolutions, statements of CCA committees, General Assembly, 1988-1990 (Box 101, Folder 36)
      - Responses / letters of support
        - "A Personal Statement in Regard to the Recent CCA Incident in Singapore" - signed by 30+ individuals, 1988-04 (Box 101, Folder 37)
        - From Asian churches: India, Indonesia, Japan, 1988 (Box 101, Folder 38)
        - From Asian churches: Korea, Pakistan, Philippines, Singapore, Sri Lanka, Thailand, 1988 (Box 101, Folder 39)
        - From Australia, New Zealand, Melanesia, 1988-1989 (Box 101, Folder 40)
        - From European churches, 1988 (Box 101, Folder 41)
        - From North American churches, 1988 (Box 101, Folder 42)
        - From World Council of Churches, 1988 (Box 101, Folder 43)
        - From various ecumenical organizations, 1988 (Box 101, Folder 44)
      - Aftermath documentation
        - Press coverage of expulsion, 1988 (Box 102, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence re. staff activities, 1987 December - 1988 January (Box 102, Folder 2)
        - Correspondence re. staff activities, 1988 February - September (Box 102, Folder 3)
        - Re. commissioning of Ron O'Grady to write book: Banished: the expulsion of the Christian Conference of Asia from Singapore and its implications, 1989-1990 (Box 102, Folder 4)
        - Proposed responses, incl. boycotting of Singapore as venue for ecumenical gatherings, 1988-1990 (Box 102, Folder 5)
      - Background material re. oppression
        - Detention of 16 individuals in Singapore, 1987
          - Chronology of events, info. re. detainees, 1987-1988 (Box 102, Folder 6)
          - Ministry of Home Affairs press release re. Marxist conspiracy, 1987 May (Box 102, Folder 7)
          - Responses from ecumenical organizations, churches, and other groups, 1987 (Box 102, Folder 8)
          - Emergency Committee for Human Rights in Singapore updates #1-28, 1987-1989 (Box 102, Folder 9-11)
          - Additional communications from Emergency Committee for Human Rights in Singapore, 1987-1989 (Box 102, Folder 12)
          - Report and press releases of International Mission of Jurists to Singapore, 1987 (Box 102, Folder 13)
          - Report of Amnesty International mission to Singapore, June 1987 (Box 102, Folder 14)
          - Press coverage, 1987-1989 (Box 102, Folder 15-16)
        - Singapore Maintenance of Religious Harmony Bill, 1990
          - Text of Bill and responses, 1990 (Box 102, Folder 17)
        - From elsewhere in Asia
          - India, 1986 (Box 102, Folder 18)
          - Malaysia, 1987-1988 (Box 102, Folder 19)
  - Reports and statements
    - Policy and planning
      - "East Asia Christian Conference and the Roman Catholic Church (1964-1970)" - report and background correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 102, Folder 24)
      - "Priorities 1976-1977" (Box 102, Folder 25)
      - "Towards a New Thrust and Structure for the CCA: A Proposal" and background documents, 1995 (Box 102, Folder 26)
      - Quarterly report, 2003 (Box 102, Folder 27)
      - "A Five-Year Plan, 2005-2010" (Box 102, Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous
      - "Towards a Christian Strategy in East Asia" by Charles W. Ranson, 1950 (Box 102, Folder 29)
      - "Some Thoughts on the WCC - EACC Relationships" by Dai Kitagawa, 1958 (Box 102, Folder 30)
      - "Changing Patterns in Missionary Strategy" by Alan A. Brash, 1958 (Box 102, Folder 31)
      - "Asia and the Ecumenical Movement (1895-1961)" by Hans-Ruedi Weber, 1966 (Box 102, Folder 32)
      - "Ecumenical Participation by Japan and Korea" by Sang-Jung Park, 1978 (Box 102, Folder 33)
      - Proposals submitted to CCA by Peter Holden re. peace building and advocacy for refugees, 1993 (Box 102, Folder 34)
      - Travel reports - Bangladesh, Burma, China, 1975-1980 (Box 102, Folder 35)
      - Travel reports - Nepali community, Pakistan, Philippines, Taiwan, 1971-1976 (Box 102, Folder 36)
      - Travel reports - Australia, Fiji, Indonesia, Philippines, 1995-1996 (Box 102, Folder 37)
- Administrative Records, Series II
  - EACC-era governance / correspondence
    - Continuation Committee
      - Minutes, meeting in Kuala Lumpur, 1959 (Box 102, Folder 38)
      - Documents and reports, meeting in Bangalore, 1961 (Box 102, Folder 39)
      - Minutes and reports, meeting in Hong Kong, 1966 (Box 102, Folder 40)
      - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 102, Folder 41)
      - Agenda and information, meeting in Atami, Japan, 1970 (Box 102, Folder 42)
      - Committee and program reports, meeting in Atami, 1970 (Box 102, Folder 43)
      - Worship, meeting in Atami, 1970 (Box 102, Folder 44)
      - Agenda and information, meeting in Singapore, 1971 (Box 102, Folder 45)
      - Reference papers, meeting in Singapore, 1971 (Box 102, Folder 46-47)
      - Other reports and documents, meeting in Singapore, 1971 (Box 102, Folder 48)
      - Miscellaneous financial information, including re. EACC Special Ecumenical Fund, 1967-1973 (Box 102, Folder 49)
      - Preparatory readings for Bangalore meeting, 1961 (Box 107, Folder 15)
    - Working Committee
      - Meeting documents, 1957 (Box 62, Folder 20)
      - Minutes, 1958, 1959, 1967 (Box 62, Folder 21)
      - Meeting documents and correspondence, 1969 (Box 62, Folder 22)
      - Minutes and documents, 1972 (Box 62, Folder 23)
      - Meeting documents and correspondence, 1972 (Box 62, Folder 24)
    - Staff meetings
      - Minutes and correspondence, 1963-1973 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Officers' meetings
      - Minutes, 1959, 1968, 1969, 1971 (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - Other committees and correspondence
      - Policy and Structure Committee, 1971 (Box 103, Folder 1-2)
      - Urban Industrial Mission Committee, 1971 (Box 103, Folder 3)
      - Laymen Abroad Committee, 1971-1974 (Box 103, Folder 4)
      - Christian Education and Lay Training Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 103, Folder 5)
      - Committee on Medical Work, 1970 (Box 106, Folder 15)
  - CCA-era governance / correspondence
    - Officers' Meetings
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1973 (Box 64, Folder 20)
      - Minutes, 1974 (Box 64, Folder 21)
      - Minutes and correspondence, 1975 (Box 64, Folder 22)
      - Minutes and correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Executive Committee
      - Minutes, notes, and correspondence, 1973 (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - Meeting documents and correspondence, 1974 (Box 67, Folder 2)
      - Minutes and correspondence, 1975 (Box 67, Folder 3)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1976 (Box 67, Folder 4)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1977 (Box 67, Folder 5a)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1978 (Box 67, Folder 5b)
      - Minutes and documents, 1982 (Box 67, Folder 6)
      - Minutes, 1983 (Box 67, Folder 7)
      - Meeting documents, 1983 (Box 67, Folder 8)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1984 (Box 67, Folder 9)
      - Minutes, 1985 (Box 67, Folder 10)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1986 (Box 67, Folder 11)
      - Meeting documents, 1986 (Box 67, Folder 12)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1988 (Box 67, Folder 13)
      - Minutes and documents, 1990 (Box 67, Folder 14)
      - Minutes and documents, 1992 (Box 67, Folder 15)
      - Minutes, documents, 1993 (Box 67, Folder 16a)
      - Meeting documents, and correspondence, 1993 (Box 67, Folder 16b)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1994 (Box 67, Folder 17)
      - Meeting documents, 1994 (Box 67, Folder 18)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1995 March (Box 67, Folder 19)
      - Meeting documents, 1995 March (Box 67, Folder 20)
      - Meeting documents, 1995 March (Box 67, Folder 21)
      - Meeting documents, 1995 June (Box 67, Folder 22)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1996 (Box 67, Folder 23)
      - Documents and correspondence, 1997 (Box 67, Folder 24)
      - Minutes and documents, 1998 (Box 67, Folder 25)
      - Minutes and documents, 1999 (Box 67, Folder 26)
      - Minutes, 2000 (Box 67, Folder 27)
      - Minutes and documents, 2001 (Box 67, Folder 28)
      - Meeting documents and correspondence, 2002 (Box 67, Folder 29)
      - Meeting documents, 2003 (Box 103, Folder 7)
      - Meeting preparation and schedule - Taipei, 2006 (Box 103, Folder 37)
    - General Committee
      - Minutes and meeting documents, 1973 (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Meeting documents and correspondence, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Applications, 1977 (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Schedules and corrspondence, 1980 (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1981 (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Meeting documents, 1982 (Box 63, Folder 6)
      - Meeting documents and correspondence, 1983 (Box 63, Folder 7)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1984 (Box 63, Folder 8)
      - Minutes and meeting documents, 1985 (Box 63, Folder 9)
      - Minutes and meeting documents, 1987 (Box 63, Folder 10-12)
      - Minutes and meeting documents, 1988 (Box 63, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence and articles, 1988 (Box 63, Folder 14)
      - Minutes and meeting documents, 1989 (Box 63, Folder 15)
      - Articles and correspondence, 1989 (Box 63, Folder 16)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1990 (Box 63, Folder 17-18)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1991 (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 103, Folder 10)
      - Minutes and meeting documents, 1992 (Box 64, Folder 2-4)
      - Minutes and meeting documents, 1994 (Box 64, Folder 5-7)
      - Worship and other documents, 1994 (Box 64, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 64, Folder 9-10)
      - Minutes and meeting documents, 1995 (Box 64, Folder 11)
      - Supporting documents, 1995 (Box 64, Folder 12)
      - Meeting documents, 1995 (Box 64, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 64, Folder 14)
      - Documents and reports, 1996-1997 (Box 64, Folder 15)
      - Meeting documents, 1998 (Box 64, Folder 16)
      - Minutes and documents, 2000 (Box 64, Folder 17)
      - Meeting documents, 2003 (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - Roundtable Meetings
      - Minutes, documents, and notes, 1996 (Box 62, Folder 15)
      - Minutes and documents, 1997 (Box 62, Folder 16)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1999 (Box 62, Folder 17)
      - Minutes and correspondence, 2000 (Box 62, Folder 18)
      - Meeting documents, 2001 (Box 62, Folder 19)
    - Executive Staff Meetings
      - Minutes, 1975, 1979 (Box 66, Folder 5)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1981-1985 (Box 66, Folder 6)
      - Documents and correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 103, Folder 12)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 7)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1990 (Box 66, Folder 8)
      - Meeting documents and correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 66, Folder 9)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1995 (Box 66, Folder 10)
      - Supporting documents, 1995 (Box 66, Folder 11)
      - Meeting documents and correspondence - 1, 1996 (Box 66, Folder 12)
      - Meeting documents and correspondence - 2, 1996 (Box 66, Folder 13a)
      - Meeting documents and correspondence - 3, 1996 (Box 66, Folder 13b)
      - Minutes and correspondence, 1997 (Box 66, Folder 14)
      - Meeting documents and correspondence -1, 1997 (Box 66, Folder 15a)
      - Meeting documents and correspondence - 2, 1997 (Box 66, Folder 15b)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 66, Folder 16a)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 66, Folder 16b)
      - Documents and correspondence, 2000-2002 (Box 103, Folder 11)
      - Minutes and documents, 2002 (Box 66, Folder 17)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 2003 (Box 66, Folder 18)
    - Staff Meetings
      - Meeting notes and documents, 1973 (Box 65, Folder 2)
      - Meeting notes, documents, and correspondence, 1974 (Box 65, Folder 3)
      - Meeting notes and documents, 1974 (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Minutes and documents, 1975 (Box 65, Folder 5)
      - Minutes and documents, 1976 (Box 65, Folder 6)
      - Minutes and documents, 1977 (Box 65, Folder 7)
      - Minutes and documents, 1978 (Box 65, Folder 8)
      - Minutes and documents, 1979 (Box 65, Folder 9a)
      - Minutes and documents, 1980-1981 (Box 65, Folder 9b)
      - Minutes and documents, 1982 (Box 65, Folder 10)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 103, Folder 8)
      - Minutes and documents, 1983 (Box 65, Folder 11)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1984 (Box 65, Folder 12)
      - Minutes and documents, 1985 (Box 65, Folder 13)
      - Minutes and documents, 1986 (Box 65, Folder 14)
      - Minutes and documents, 1987 (Box 65, Folder 15)
      - Minutes and documents, 1988 (Box 65, Folder 16)
      - Minutes and documents, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 17)
      - Minutes and documents, 1990 (Box 65, Folder 18)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1991 (Box 65, Folder 19)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1992 (Box 65, Folder 20)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence, 1993 (Box 65, Folder 21)
      - Minutes, documents, and correspondence - 1, 1994 (Box 65, Folder 22)